excellent today we're talking about coin
shuffle practical decentralized clean
magazine for Bitcoin so let's get
started so we're looking at a 2014 paper
by Ruffing Marino Sanchez and Kate
here's the other paper itself last week
just a reminder we talked about sneaker
coin joint and the summary was that we
could have a non-interactive coin joint
between two participants if the proposer
if one of the two participants assumes
likely UT exo-m's tweaks a revealed
public key with a difficult and shared
secret and then it takes this partially
signed Bitcoin transaction and
broadcasts into a public forum where the
other participants may sign it when they
see it so essentially we talked about
non interactive coin joints so far we've
talked about knapsack who enjoyed
snicker today's coin shuffle and then
next week's will be decided at the end
of this call you can find out everything
on our wasabi research club github okay
so we're gonna reproduce last week's
topic which is the problem with current
coin joints so the problem that we
talked about last week we retire on this
week as well is that they require
coordination so last week it was more
about interactivity this week it's about
coordination so coordination is a you
know is potentially a problem because of
things like privacy or the fact that the
coordinator becomes a central point of
failure so the question today is going
to be can we create coin joints without
coordination just like last time we
talked about what it would take to to
create a coin joint and really it comes
down to knowing the inputs the outputs
and the signatures now if we think
deeply about this it's not just about
knowing inputs outputs and signatures
you know inputs and outputs change
outputs aren't necessarily anonymous so
participants can can declare their
inputs and declare their change outputs
but we also have to find out all of the
participants mixed outputs so there are
anonymous outputs and we need to find
this out without having them reveal that
the link between their outputs and and
the fact they belong in the coin
so if you look at how wasabi does this
with a coordinator
well wasabi uses what's called secure
multi-party computation or essentially
just your signatures imagine Orion blind
signing of outputs in order to allow for
outputs to be anonymously submitted so
users first that will register their
inputs and they'll have a blinded output
signed by the server at which point
later they will submit the unblinded
output to the coordinator and the
coordinator doesn't know who is the
person that submitted the the output
only the that person is valid because
the coordinator did a blind signing of
the output okay so coin shuffle in
summary is just wasabi without the
coordinator
so using descent protocol for
communicating anonymous outputs by
participants and we'll look at that
briefly and then well there are no
questions so far right or girl comments
no okay so when chef Allah so we can
imagine six participants in particularly
one imagined and ordered six
participants so we'll have that the left
the red individual is the is the first
and the last participant is the purple
and there's all the participants in
between and so just it's for the purpose
of illustration it's easier if they're
colorful and so essentially what we want
to do is that these participants they
want to submit their inputs they want to
submit their change outputs but they
also want to submit a blinded output and
output that no one that is completely
anonymous to the rest of the
participants and they want to do this
without a coordinator that is
essentially controlling how this goes so
essentially what you have here is what
what the cord room will look like at the
end is it should look like a bunch of
inputs from all set participants some
change outputs and some outputs that are
of equal size that we don't know who
they belong to
so we have six ordered participants and
we have an anonymous coin joint output
so it's trivial to get the change
outputs done and the inputs done because
those can be linked together and
participants don't have to hide the fact
that they are the ones submitting that
information now we're going to see how a
participant in this case is going to
anonymously submit a an anonymous output
so in this case what we have is we have
a the first participant is the regular
sprint so if you look at this colorful
little blob in the very middle is the
red address okay that's like the
unencrypted red addresses right in the
center there and then what the red
participants going to do is that person
is going to encrypt that red address
against Purple's public key and take
that encrypted data and encrypt it
against blue as public Heat and so forth
and then that data is encrypted against
green's public key and so forth and so
what you have and this is familiar to
some of you it's like an onion right so
it's it's a layered encryption so it's
encrypted against purple blue green
yellow orange so then red will take this
blob and pass it to the next person in
line which in this case is orange right
now orange will decrypt one layer
because orange it holds the orange
public key so orange can decrypt the
layer from Red's address and
simultaneously add oranges address also
encrypted in the same onion scheme being
encrypted first against the purple key
then the blue of them the green and then
lastly the yellow and now the orange has
two blobs just to pass on to the next
individual or I'm just going to shuffle
them so you know just like this and
again yellow now is going to submit his
own address unwrapped
the two layers of yellow on the orange
and the red
and then again encrypt everything so
that it's layer to give the next three
participants and shuffle and send over
to the next layer and so you know things
repeat over and over again and finally
what happens is that purple who's the
last individual has all of the addresses
and can and can has no idea who they
belong to
so from the perspective of purple only
purple address is known to be to belong
to it every other address belongs to
someone else and it's not clear who so
for an oranges perspective you know only
the orange address is known the other
five addresses aren't completely a
mystery and from yellow it's the same
idea and and from red and that pretty
much is you can you just go but because
I think it's incorrect yes go back like
two more or something yes so so you see
right now
yellow only has three outputs three
three onion encrypted stuff but actually
it's everyone broadcast so okay sorry go
ahead
I know it's incorrect but I can't
explain any time yeah okay yeah so it
definitely can be incorrect I don't to
claim that I'm hundred percent but I
think the idea overall were and the aim
is so that in an ordered fashion can
submit their addresses and not have the
address linked to them and it's done
exactly it was sort of in this sort of
way
yes yes I think I think what a davis is
telling us is correct because that's
this saying that i understood what i
read that the paper everyone
i mean you you decrypt the previous
participants with your private key
because the the message was encrypted
with your public key because previously
there is an announcement phase where all
the participants share their public keys
so in this order you create these onion
layers right and is that how how this is
telling us now allison is correct is
that as you said first the announcement
announcing the public key so everyone
here aviv igor lucas max oh I don't know
if you want pseudonym or sorry Rafael
and me
so everyone announces are his own public
key and everyone has to think up a
message or or an output right a Bitcoin
address and we have to encrypt that
Bitcoin address everyone has to encrypt
it in a specific order
so first what we've done to Igor than to
Lucas and so on and then we broadcast
all the encrypted messages so that's how
you can shuffle them that's what is
well no because no I what I understood
is what a Vives is be saying that it is
an order it is in order
yes and the messages is passing one by
one and everybody the creeps the the the
the coins with their with their public
keys shuffle the the encrypted addresses
yes and pass that to the next one so in
the end the the latest one the the
latest participant not the one in the in
the finalist step or I can finally
decrypt all the the addresses except of
course the one that belong to do him
understanding of if can you go back to
to read my question is at this point
okay good go to the next one at this
point
orange only has two or has all the
encrypted messages only two that's
what's incorrect Orange has oiled
encrypted messages everyone encrypt
their message in a specific order and
broadcasts all the messages red starts
decrypting the layer the the the upper
layer of the messages and Shaffers it
then orange starts decrypting his layer
and shoppers so all the messages right
everyone has all other messages all the
encrypted messages that's the point
it actually seems like what Adam is
saying makes a lot of sense so there's
no reason why everyone couldn't submit
all of their addresses like the way red
did it
so that mmm-hmm and that's how you can
put it into a peer-to-peer network where
everyone root costs every message it's
it's not really passing Allah maybe
maybe it can be but it's not really
passing around the messages from peer to
peer but broadcasts all the messages for
everyone all the time I did think that
it was sequential in that red had to
communicate to orange and orange had to
communicate to yellow and yellow had to
communicate to green and that it wasn't
like I mean I guess you could do it
publicly because you can keep announcing
everything and only the the right person
can decrypt that layer but but I didn't
think that it was sequential I mean just
think about it what if red because in
this case red doesn't shuffle anything
then he read cannot make sure that the
things are suffered correctly right
orange can only partially make sure that
a two thing is suffered now I actually
wrote code for it so I am pretty sure
what I'm saying anyway yes can we agree
in this or or or someone would like to
have objection I'm very happy to you can
see this because I think that the point
is the same that the goal is the same is
that these peers want to essentially mix
these outputs and not have connection
between who submitted what right okay so
um right so here is what I did
I'm kind of summarize we thought of
because the final okay yeah I mean so
the summary is is here as well but the
the the the summary is that yeah of what
happened is that six participants got
together and are essentially submitting
their anonymous addresses outputs in
such a way where when purple finally
opens all six addresses purple can link
those addresses to any of the past
participants and it's done with like
onion layer encryption and shuffling so
those outputs are shuffled across
participants Adam says that all six
addresses are shuffled in with every
single step and that could very well be
the case but at the end you have six
addresses that are unlinked okay okay so
so here is the in the paper it's
explained so you can see in the top
right Alice has this layered encryption
and she passes off to Bob for decrypt
who passes dr. Charlie decrypt and and
you can see this sort of mix mixed
network yeah and on the bottom left you
have a point row and that's been signed
on the bottom right do you have a
pointer and that's not been signed
because someone tampered with the
addresses and added an invalid address
to the coin joint so the big thing to
talk about with Quinn story of you can I
show maybe you understand it better
based on that sure
[Music]
I am sharing my screen right okay do you
see it yeah okay then then it's a
problem because it's not in the video
just like last time I had to cut it out
and anyway very quickly then we have
Ali's Bob and Satoshi and everyone
broadcasts their public keys I run this
and it's going to be this this comes out
so everyone broadcasts their public key
and then these onions and these are the
the encrypted messages and rip that for
everyone and then everyone starts to
decrypt their messages one by one
everyone starts to decrypt all the
messages orderly layers and and at the
end we get we get get a script like like
a bitcoins Bitcoin scripts right that's
that's the Bitcoin address it just creep
up key and not a Bitcoin address so
anyway if you see that yeah it works
okay I don't want to ruin the video with
this so so go ahead okay pretty much at
the end here the big concern right when
you consider getting rid of the central
coordinator and instead having peers
during this process themselves is is the
time it will take and the computational
take from the peers so in the equation
ax paper they took participants and set
them up on a low
network and then on a global network
with a certain amount of latency from
one side of the net to the other side of
the network and here you can see the
time it takes oh if you look at the
local network where there's almost no
latency it looks like an Alinea increase
in the time it takes with 50
participants you have 30 seconds 40
seconds of time it takes for essentially
that we're just best to do the entire
dance from start to finish and then with
the global network you can see that the
time it takes is much much more because
every single individual needs to hear
the latest state and then decrypt that
situation and then pass it on to the
next individual who will who needs to
then so it is sequential whether
individuals are talking directly to each
other
or in public broadcasting to everyone
it's still the case that that these
onions have to be decrypted in a
sequential way so the more participants
you have the more time it takes and on
the right there is the average
processing time per node yeah so yeah
and we also have descent which is what
this is based on they also did a similar
test of the shuffle time for you know 44
nodes with varying size here it's one
megabyte of data of encrypted data
that's being shuffled over 44 nodes you
can see it takes several minutes so 15
minutes by 44 nodes and over here there
was three minutes by by 40 or 50
participants so yeah in summary rather
than have a secure multi-party
computation with a coordinator coin
shuffle a solved problem of constructing
a quorum with just participants
themselves using this the dissent
messaging protocol commercial
participants shovel their anonymous
outputs until all outputs are made
available to all
since without a link anybody spent to an
output and the biggest drawback is the
time cost as the number of participants
grows and then the advantages that
there's no coordinator to to attack
during denial of service and that's
pretty much what I think needs to be
said about this so yeah believe it that
thank you
let's continue questions and discussions
and then ideas and later on topic for
next weekend so yes questions I have a
comment
well first of all I I think I I don't
know what your implementation is based
on probably is in a new version that we
are not that we don't know but I again I
understood the same data we've explained
us and in fact there is a very
simplified version or very simplified
explanation in Quito in Bitcoin talked
about it by by team one of the of the
creator of this is King III understand
the same whatever I read it but anyway
that's one point
the other point doesn't have onions then
who's gonna read decrypt
his onions for other people no Ally so
in this case the red doesn't creep
he only encrypts the the output right
increase the output with all the public
keys of the other participants in order
so the next one in this case the orange
the orange one the creeps with his
public key it remove one layer
yes and just encrypt everything again
with the pin and the dead life this
layer is the the yellow one right so
yellow the Crypt remove that layer mix
those call those addresses and encrypt
again with yes is what a baby is doing
so in the end all the old a our
addresses has only one layer of
encryption that is the one belonging to
the today to that guy what color is that
purple I think okay so purple decrypt
all the addresses yes except the one
that belong to to him and perform just
the latest shuffle and broadcast that
list of outputs to everyone so after
that is the face of the the next step is
creating the the transaction so nobody
knows what output belong to to the rest
I see okay a maybe then III don't know
it I didn't understand this properly
then schemes work I mean I know that my
scheme is working I and now that you
explained what you're doing is it seems
to me that's working too so and that
that results in less encryption and
decryption so less Network messages
maybe it's faster so yeah okay yeah I
think I have an idea
here for this scheme because you know if
in the first phase I mean in the in the
announcement face participants could
announce their public keys and also how
much money they want to participate with
right for example Alice can say this is
my public key and I want to participate
with one Bitcoin Bob this is my public
key and I want to participate with 0.83
bitcoins sorry yes is the media is
changing the protocol just a bit right
because if everybody knows the public
keys and and the amount that other
participants want to participate with
then what participants can do is
creating the outputs yes not only the
addresses but also the amount of that
addresses using the snap sucks right
because remember that was one of the
idea that what the the latest proposal
that was never published by I don't
remember the name of the guy that was
with us in the knapsack and episode
let's say he said this a new version
that I never published that is the
participants only know only need to know
the amount of the other participants so
they can split their outputs in such a
way yes that they can create a knapsack
transaction right so in that way we
could encrypt more than one address but
also the amount so you don't need to
shuffle right because the idea of oh
well yes you need shuffle so you can
shuffle but in the end what the purple
guy will receive is a lot of output
transactions yes with the no only
descript
but also they did the amount and that
will be at not sack transaction so it it
could be used for unequal outputs to
using what we learn in the first episode
and I think that's a very important idea
that's a good job Lucas seriously so
anyone have questions or should I go
with mine okay okay go ahead a vision
no you asked you a question first okay
it was it was a general question about
denial of service or rather simple
attacks I mean we can use a central
coordinator right to depend UTX those
but and we have a feature economic
disincentive attack but there are no in
coin so how can we defend against okay
so that's a really great question
it's addressed in the paper and in the
protocol itself so the the phases you
know there's the first phases the
announcement phase then there's the
shuffling phase what happens later is
that if after the shuffling phase if you
get to an undesired outcome namely the
addresses in the that are appearing are
not belonging to all the participants
you know someone added two addresses or
someone didn't shuffle correctly there
is a way to go through the blame phase
where essentially all participants
reenact what they did and you can tell
if someone did something bad so you can
do blame but that also is takes time and
it's arguable that it would be it's it's
easier to attack this sort of system
then now Assadi coordinator is your
answer it was correct
I just want maybe Trisha easier to say
this way that if someone misbehaves that
obviously everyone detected because the
final Cohen joined doesn't happen
so everyone just exposes all the actions
that they take with the without their
without except their outputs except
their Bitcoin addresses so and the
protocol can run but because if if you
give out all the actions that you take
during the run of the protocol to
everyone that hey here is my my private
key for example I signed my messages
with this then you can tell exactly who
misbehaved and you can rule him out and
you can run the protocol with the
remaining honest participants this this
is something
I have a comment because that try in
fact there is some advanced techniques
in in in the in the other paper basing
it is the conscious plus plus that I'm
not familiar with yet but listen civil
attacks are hard to prevent in in
conjoint right it's if it's really hard
right now because in this case for
example if you are one guy that
participated with multiple identities
let's say yes imagine I am red and you
are orange jell-o like blue and bla bla
bla so there is nothing I can do
yes but but Daniel of service attacks
can be I mean I think it's not a naive
alternative but it works pretty well
that is okay someone didn't sign the
transaction right it is easy to see to
know that so you can just burn that coin
as we do try again sooner or later that
guy will run out of money
probably is not the best way just
switches okay I cannot hear anything
oh sorry
and III for this division never said
with the captain
I love Britt but I'm the typical self
our Sigma max sorry pocket
actually I just max do you have some
software of feature that needs you when
you're not speaking or something like
that because I see that you are muting
and unmuting in high frequency sorry
I didn't hear your your your your
question can you repeat please
purple the last one changes the address
changes let's say red address to his own
address then it's going to be red who
doesn't sign so you cannot really burn
red right so the way we wait but the I
can seen
I can see the transaction right the
final conjoined transaction the final
conscience transaction has in this case
one two three four five six
there are six participants let's say
there are six inputs - just to simplify
and there is one missing signature so
someone didn't sign right so in that in
that case
we can burn that coin so you can
participate again but now with the same
coin
Lukas the so this is this is exactly
what you saw in this protocol
unfortunately you can't apply the same
banning heuristics as with wasabi so
with wasabi you can't ban the coin that
did not sign in this protocol if if
someone if you end up with an unsigned
coin joint there are two reasons either
someone is not signing on purpose or in
which case you can ban the other part of
the coin that did not sign or someone
did the protocol wrong right in the case
Adam gave purple is the last person with
all of the addresses and purple
you know dumps Reds address and adds two
of Purple's addresses to the to the
mixed outputs so how do you know how
sorry yes yes yes yes sorry yes I
understand now so what you have to do in
that case it's actually quite
unfortunate is that every person has to
reveal to the entire group what
information they received and what they
encrypted and each and and what they
decrypted and and by doing this the
guilty party will be revealed but the
annoying part is that this also takes
several minutes of of everyone sort of
presenting what they have and then you
have to recursively go through and see
which person you know tampered with the
the information and if you can waste
three minutes of time then you know
arguably it's premature dos attack yes
it's clear now yes sorry it was a silly
question but anyway you remember
Adam Gibson tell us right they did the
attend yellow service attacks is because
someone wants to prevent this for
happening and if there is not incentive
because you cannot steal money so if the
result daniel of service attack is i
mean there are no incentives right at
the beginning it at least for this kind
of attacks so a naive implementation can
work at the beginning at least i mean an
implementation that doesn't implement
any Daniel of service attacks prevention
mechanism so it the point is is that
with this protocol you do have a blame
face and you can't point out the guilty
party it's just it takes additional time
so all I'm gonna say is is is that
looking at the trade-offs of this
protocol as soon as we start talking
about large number of participants more
than 50 we're gonna have pretty severe
problems with with latency and I think
there's an issue where the longer it
takes for round to happen the more
likely someone is to lose connection or
or or be a part of the problem so I
think it's just not practical to do coin
joins this way one more thing that's
interesting in this is that here the
dose protection
so here the coin join happens between
the honest participants in Vasavi we
always forget the state we take down the
required anonymity said but anyone can
register to that not only those who are
who were already registered in the
previous failing round right this I'm
not sure which direction is the
but this might be something that we can
consider later on any thoughts on this
can you say that again I am sorry
understand sorry
yeah I was not clear enough so here if
fails then the next round is going to
happen between the participants without
the malicious party in Vasavi if round
fails then the next round the anonymity
set required anonymity set will be
lowered but Bobby doesn't make sure that
those people who were in the failing
previous round the honest people from
the failing previous round will mix do
you understand the difference it's a
subtle nuanced one but it's it's
somewhat important I'm gonna say yes
play I honestly do not think I
understood okay so there is a round
basta be Co enjoying possibly or coin
shove doesn't matter the round fares
what happens in Queens offer the same
participants the same participants will
Co enjoying it it is coin shuffle in
wasabi it's not the same participants
possibly just lowers the required number
with the number of malicious
participants but still in that round
anyone can register okay so two things
about that then so firstly coin shuffle
if a coin shuffle round fails it goes
through the blame face it points out
someone to blame and then it does a
conjoin another coin shuffle
doubt that participates that's that's
what I understood yes exactly and in
terms of in terms of wasabi
I thought wasabi was you know if a coin
joint fails it's because someone didn't
sign and that that one coin that is
didn't sign is banned for example and
all the coins try again - that one coin
so I guess I'm confused on both issues
you are right
except the end that not all the Queens
who already registered it's not those
who re doing the exact same or failing
ground without malicious person but it's
it's it's a completely new round
anyone can come the malicious person is
bound but any new coin can come in in
coin shuffle
new coin cannot come in okay okay so
that I had that I understand and I
didn't know that was the case and it's a
very axis it's a very small detail but
yeah yes it's important all right next
question what is secure multi-party
computation for me because I can just be
a Wikipedia it's a question
next time baby
okay so one more thing that since we are
come since we are comparing it to wasabi
there is there is a comment from or
actually it's not even a comment anyway
I'm just going to read it I'm not sure
if it's from the paper or or it's a
comment from Bitcoin talks so Maxwell
sketches a modification to the coin join
protocol using blind signatures to avoid
the problem of a centralized mix
learning the relation between input and
output addresses this this is this is
the show me and Cohen join just saying
and yes it's in the paper now I know
this protocol employees the anonymous
communication network tour as a blinding
as a building block to provide an link
ability in contrast coin shuffle
provides full resistance against traffic
correlation attacks by using a
decentralized high latency mix Network
run only by the participants so that
that's an important point here to write
that wasabi realized on new tour
identities
coin shuffle does not it it's doing a
mix you could even mix without
tour just on the clear night right it
would still work
but but actually I mean I was pickling
when I when I read the paper and the
shout out to hear a link but then the
the discussion that I have is I mean we
could also do zero link not on tour but
on a mix now what that work to I mean
well the Queen bear in mind that keep in
mind that all the coin shuffle
implementations are actually using the
server and you know in theory you can
use just a bulletin board server where
participants are are posting their
messages but they are actually
using for coordination and those
protection and things like that I think
so so yes you can say that Kesha is is
is is Vasavi with her store and you know
what I mean so so yes definitely but but
then you will call it coin shuffle
because coin shuffle is using a mix
night that's the thing about it well I
guess the important thing to notice that
coin shuffle doesn't make any claims
about how we structure coin joints
rather just how we communicate right so
okay sorry anyway I understand what you
say Taliah simply kind of spoke about
the positive but maybe a bit further to
the stuff to discuss what we can combine
cannot psyche with this so I'm not sure
I understood the conversation we had
earlier so what does it be that we first
do a communication around with with coin
shuffle and then we get this coin joint
transaction and then we apply cannot
back to this coin joint transaction or
how exactly would that work well
knapsack works by splitting the outputs
in depending on the amounts of the other
participants right so if you know how
much the other participants are
participating with you can split your
output in such a way that after the
process I mean you can't use two exactly
the same that we've explained us but in
the end
the the purple guy where they create all
the outputs right and those outputs yes
when you analyze those outputs there
will be more than one trivial mapping to
the inputs right so it is basically an
knapsack transaction is it clear
wouldn't that lead to like spam in the
chain which I may use the xhose or would
be like some kind of minimal amount
minimum amount of for one ugh so that's
the trade-off with the knapsack is that
yeah it the the better the knapsack the
more you th cells you need okay going
back to the today to the comment today
what Adam says yeah I mean it is
possible to use the same technology that
in this networks I mean using X or using
the X or of exploring all the messages
with all the public keys of all the
participants and in that case we could
remove tour the only problem is that we
still will be able to see their IP
addresses
something that we thought we cannot do I
mean it is possible to use that
technology to do in so the server will
not be able to know who message belong
to whom right but the IP address is
still there oh that's a very good point
because in wasabi the server doesn't
know that if some are registers to the
Kohen join did he used this used wasabi
before or not the server doesn't know
because it's on a new tour stream but
you if it Konoha
if you don't use tor then you have you
can tell that that which participants
participants which person participated
in which Cohen joins so now you can
correlate so you you actually have to
use tor for Cohen shuffle - yes that's
my point yes okay I only have one
discussion thing or all other
interesting thing that regarding Queen
shuffle is that I don't know if you guys
knew it but on Bitcoin talk the very
first page of conversation was about a
replay attack and then Tim Rafi noted
that the thing about encryption schemes
is that all our secure encryption scheme
always uses randomness for encryption to
make sure that encrypting the same
message twice does not yield the same
ciphertext the audit randomness is built
in the encryption algorithm itself one
does not have to all randomness manually
to a message before giving
to the algorithm try it take an
encryption tool and try to encrypt the
same message twice so anyways it's just
good to know I
yeah
so do you guys have any presentations
questions discussions ideas or should I
move on to something more interesting I
have no idea third question just
something that we could have in mind
that could improve our conjoined
transaction is researching if is there
any way to identify the offender in
order to remove it and and create a new
conjoin without that attacker that could
be graded I think it's not possible but
it could be good to if I don't know if
we can say okay someone didn't sign we
provide proof that of something I don't
know just to avoid creating a new round
again so it that would be really good I
think it's possible I think it it can be
it can be done and not even hard but I'm
not sure it makes sense because then
what's the attack the attack is that the
see becomes the malicious malicious CBI
comes and tries to I don't know maybe
then
I don't know it's a it's an interesting
question to explore definitely
all right so yes before we would get
into the next topic I want to talk about
something is that what direction should
this research club take now I want to
talk about just an idea of how should we
how how can we make what's the most was
the best thing to to research in Bitcoin
privacy and I have a small roadmap ish
thing and we could adjust the researches
to to that later on right now we will of
course as we discussed we will go
through the coin shuffle line but after
that so I please opinion it it's it's
something that that I've been thinking
about for a year now and it's getting
more and more solid based on the
opinions but I would like to hear yours
too and and and adjust it so this this
is the roadmap to Bitcoin privacy okay
very first thing to do is to figure out
the most blog space efficient way of
mixing coins second thing to do is to
figure out how to send money in a mix
instead of sending to yourself mixing to
yourself the third thing to do is after
these things are figured out we have to
figure out how to do it trust Leslie
fourth thing to do is figure out how to
do it in a decentralized way which I am
NOT interested in but for completeness
completeness this is something that
people might be interested in and the
fifth thing to do is figure out how to
integrate other infrastructures into
this
this new mixing technology that has just
been researched what what are these
these infrastructures those are relevant
light clients how to do it with a light
client how to do it on mobile how to do
it with hardware wallets and how how to
and are there any ways to integrate it
to the Lightning Network somehow and
rolling to the Lightning Network or
something like this so figure out the
most block space efficient way of mixing
figure out houses and dynamics how to
send in a mix instead of mixing to serve
figure out how to do it trust Leslie
does this this three strap is is what
the wasabi Research cups should be about
the integrations and later things are or
I don't know it's ten year down the line
or 20 so the do you guys agree that this
is this is a logical sequence of of
research that we could take later on
when we learn more things
I definitely agree I would it might be a
good idea to start talking about what
the how we would measure efficiency in a
coin joint you know against the block
space that it's consuming I've been
thinking a lot I know if we have time
right now to talk about like the perfect
hygiene like this would be my next next
topic to be honest that I have sub steps
for the very first step so I don't know
you should I say the sub steps or do you
want to say what you you're saying right
now
yeah don't just say what I've been
thinking about because you know we're
all thinking about privacy right now
when I when I think about the perfect
privacy on Bitcoin given what Bitcoin
allows barring layer 2 solutions to me
that perfect solution is essentially you
know every block contains one
transaction and all inputs and outputs
from all transactions are collapsed into
a single transaction and then there are
some optimization happening where people
are breaking down their inputs and they
have common outputs of similar size and
then there's nap sacking and all sorts
of fancy stuff but the idea is that the
asymptotes of privacy the best place
prices could go this is an intuition
that could be completely wrong about
this is it's just it's just every single
block is is it's just these massive
transactions that that's that's where I
think things would be going and so that
kind of points to what Adam was saying
about how to figure out how to send in a
coin joint as well because that means
that if you can receive and send and mix
all in one coin joint then all
transactions can be coin joints in the
future I think it's a so yeah we will
probably never get
or not probably we definitely never get
there but it's a good good idea to take
imagine what could be the perfect at the
best that that's possible and start to
work backwards from there yeah that's a
good so in any way for these three steps
don't really see yet what the do you
guys see the logic between these these
three steps that most efficient way of
mixing sand dynamics and then do it
trust Leslie is it does it make sense I
really would like some feedback yes I
think that's a nice idea under no it's
especially though also you know as you
mentioned later with with other
technologies like for example lightning
Network
I think an important aspect here is to
integrate getting into second layers and
Altos in a private way so doing you know
coin joins into a lightning channel
factory for example we're doing hyper
loops you know atomic swaps out of the
Lightning Network in a coin joint um but
this summer it goes together with
sending and receiving within a coin John
Doe not just into a single public key
but more advanced second layer of script
so the reason is why the Lightning
network integration is at the very very
end because everything depends on the
coin join scheme so first you you really
have to figure out how to do one chain
transactions and then you can move on to
lightning network anyway the very first
step is figure out the most blog space
efficient way of mixing coins and this
is my thinking there are two steps here
first we have to figure out how to score
mixes and second since fighting the
maximum score based on the set of inputs
is computationally infeasible an
algorithm must be
found that performs performs the best in
multiple simulations okay sorry you
asked for feedback it not totally agree
because I know that your goal has been
your goal form for probably years right
but I mean finding the most space
efficient way to make this to build this
conjoint transactions but I can say that
our goal should be the most private way
to create the conjoined transactions I
mean probably it is more expensive well
yes but I think the the the first filter
or the first goal should be to maximize
the privacy even when probably is not
the most space efficient solution just
that that is obvious what provides the
most privacy if you if you you know the
common greatest divas or you have a set
of inputs yes you get the common rate as
the user of them and every output gets
that right or let's say one Satoshi but
rather the common greatest divisor so
that that provides the best privacy but
this is an optimization problem the best
privacy by not wasting that much block
space so you know yes that's clear is
that exactly the same that I thought
when you say it is obvious yes it is
obvious but I mean we have to have a
like minimum requirement right we cannot
was the worsening the the privacy level
we have now sorry sorry the point in it
it is not easy to know what our users
want right what do you know they did
sometimes want to be able to make more
money and faster sometimes they want to
to be able to participate with less
money or this is not easy
yes so probably it could be more
efficient it space-efficient to makes
higher coins rise for example for
example instead of now we are using 0.1
0.2 0.4 of course it could be more
private say all to split all in 0.1
coins right but I don't know is the
solution if in they were in them if
trying to to achieve a more space
efficient solution if that will not
require to make bigger coins I mean to
have bigger output when the same okay we
don't know what okay I just I just have
a road map to how to get there it's a my
idea is that we take the existing data
the existing wasabi data of what
happened with wasabi what amounts people
are coming in a mix or just existing
blockchain data the point is that you
build a software that makes this
simulation and when I say the first step
is how to score mixes what I actually
mean
is to figure out how to score a chain of
mix step 1 figure out how to score 1 mix
and step to figure out how to score a
chain of mix based on real-world data
simulation so right now we are just
coring we are not really mixing we put
some naive mixing algorithm and we try
to figure out we see a transaction chain
of a mix transaction chain and we try to
figure out how the hell should we score
that mix and then we say ok let's use
knapsack for that and we run a knapsack
for the exact same data that we're on
our previous naive mix and then we
compare our scores that hey did not suck
score better or the previous naive mix
score better does that make sense for
you yes it makes sense in itself is
about testing basically with different
algorithm the only the only thing that
we have to have in mind progress that
giving we makes zero point one at a time
yes basically yes people with a lot of
money I don't know probably 1,000
bitcoins it's not currently mixing with
with wasabi probably yes because it will
take if they want to make it right
it could take a lot so probably what we
see in our conjoined transactions that
information is already constrained by
our outputs right so that that's it just
was a comment yes
[Music]
have to figure out implementation time
that should we take the possibly over
the data or should we look at instead
the wasabi mix data instead should we
look at the input amounts on the
blockchain just randomly recently yeah
that's a methodology issue and that's
something to figure out and now going
back to the wasabi research cup because
this is the first step that we should
think about how to how to arrange the
inputs and outputs and we went down the
path of coin shuffle I think we can use
it for our advantage because the thing
is even after we figure out how to
arrange the inputs and outputs we have
to figure out how to do it in a trust
less way and it's like thoughtful it's
like it's a really hard problem but
that's when the coin shuffle line of
research comes in and at the end of that
line of research there is cache fusion
which is probably solving this problem
and which is something that I wouldn't
take as it is but I would really love to
know the the techniques that they are
using so we can go through the coin
shuffle line of research which is with
this coin shuffle now next time as Lucas
suggested we do something about the mix
networks and Tim referring the author of
coin shuffle suggested to look into the
dining cryptographers network it's a
paper and then of course coin shuffle
plus plus and then cache fusion and
after we we look into cache fusion which
our hope is that it either solves our
problem or provides
or armors of us with the necessary tools
to to Tucker
later the trust lessness problem then we
can move on to go enjoin analysis and
after the coin shuffle things we can
move on to coin Johnny Quinn Joe in
analysis stuff like coin join Sudoku
boards man maybe an absurd code or or
whatever so so we drop the coordination
issue we we get into the the the
subset-sum issue but we started with
knapsack that's that's my idea so and
and and at that point we could actually
start to research how to arrange the
amounts how to score the mixes right
that's the first one so this is my
long-term idea i have an intuition about
scoring mixes that it will be quite hard
to do this and you know i know that we
can apply some basic heuristics you know
for example take the volume and
multiplied by the number of participants
or this or that but it's it's just not
trivial thinking about how to score a
mix in especially because if we decide
you know some function accurately
consumes transaction and then gives a
good score whatever function we decide
will shape the direction of the mixing
in the future so i think that this will
be quite a tough thing to not just
present a function to score mix but also
to justify where this function is the
best approximation i I think nap sock is
the knob stock paper is a perfect basis
for that because what they did there is
they counted the likelihood between
inputs and outputs to belong together
but they also counted the likelihood
between inputs and the inputs
and outputs and outputs and if you adopt
those numbers somehow just wait with
blocks paste used and you apply the
whole concept to a mix of transit to do
a chain of mixed transactions if instead
of just a single mix then that might
work I don't know I I think that could
work like that
is it is it is it feasible to calculate
the subsets of like a large coin join
like efficiently in comedian nah it's a
5 inputs 5 outputs that could be done 6
I don't think so
okay so of course yes so the coin shove
shuffle line at the end with Cash Fusion
is this is this good for the next three
weeks
so next dining cryptographer networks
then coin shuffle plus plus then cash
fusion and then we can move on to to the
first step I agree yes I think that's
good but maybe in this slide how about
increasing the frequency because I have
more capacity to maybe do I don't know
to call so week for example it takes
time to read the papers and think about
and it's not so easy